Finding Aid for Nathan W. Shock Papers 1906-1989
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Gerontological Society of America (GSA)
  - 1st Conference on Curriculum Development and Research Training in Social Gerontology, Miami, December 13-15, 1964 (Box 40)
  - 2nd Conference on Curriculum Development and Research Training in Social Gerontology, Williamsburg, May 6-8, 1965 (Box 40)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1950-1976 (Box 40)
    - 1984-1988 (Box 40)
    - Goals, 1988 (Box 40)
    - Staff activities reports, 1983-1985 (Box 40)
- Other Organizations
  The Other Organizations series (3.5 linear feet) is an alphabetically arranged file of organizations with which Dr. Shock was associated in the period of the 1940s to the 1980s; in many cases he served as a consultant or on the advisory board of such groups as the American Psychological Association, Loyal Order of the Moose, and the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission.
  - Alliance for Aging Research, 1987 (Box 40)
  - American Aging Association, Inc. (AGE), 1971-1987 (Box 40)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1956-1958 (Box 40)
  - American Association of Retired Persons (AARP), 1958-1975 (Box 40)
  - American Federation for Aging Research (AFAR), 1980-1988; 6 folders (Box 40)
  - American Geriatrics Society, 1950-1983; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - American Health Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 40)
  - American Heart Association, 1984 (Box 40)
  - American Longevity Association
    - 1980-1982 (Box 40)
    - Longevity Letter, 1984-1986 (Box 40)
  - American Physiological Society, 1948-1976; 2 folders (Box 41)
  - American Psychological Association
    - Division of Physiological-Comparative Psychology, 1948 (Box 41)
    - Division 20, Adult Development and Aging, 1947-1985; 9 folders (Box 41)
    - Division 3, Experimental Psychology, 1965-1985 (Box 41)
    - Division 6, Physiological and Comparative Psychology, 1962-1970 (Box 41)
    - Conference on Skill and Employment, Bethesda, April 24-27, 1955 (Box 41)
  - American Society for the Study of Arteriosclerosis, 1948-1955 (Box 41)
  - Association for the Advancement of Aging Research, 1968-1974 (Box 41)
  - Association of American Medical Colleges, 1982 (Box 41)
  - British Society for Research on Aging (Box 41)
  - Gerontological Research Foundation (Box 41)
  - Industrial Research Institute (Box 42)
  - International Organization for the Study of Human Development (Box 42)
  - International Senior Citizens Association (Box 42)
  - Loyal Order of the Moose, Moosehaven, Orange Park, Florida
    - Survey Report, 1946 (Box 42)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 42)
    - 1949 (Box 42)
    - 1950 (Box 42)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 42)
    - 1953 (Box 42)
    - Moosehaven Booster, 1950-1959 (Box 42)
  - Medical Memorial Fund (New York) (Box 42)
  - National Advisory Committee on Industrial Employment of Older People, 1956 (Box 42)
  - National Committee on the Aging, 1951-1960; 4 folders
    - Technical Committee, 1954; 1958 (Box 42)
  - National Council of Senior Citizens, 1974 (Box 42)
  - National Council on the Aging, 1961-1988; 5 folders (Box 42)
  - National Social Welfare Assembly, Inc., 1956-1957 (Box 43)
  - National Voluntary Organization, 1950-1952 (Box 43)
  - Psychonomic Society, 1984 (Box 43)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1941-1966; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Baltimore County/City Commission on Aging
    - Baltimore County Commission on Aging, 1961-1967; 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Baltimore City Commission on Aging, Waxter Center, 1972 (Box 43)
  - Maryland Commission on Aging, 1958-1975; 7 folders (Box 43)
  - University of Maryland, Gerontology Center, 1973 (Box 43)
  - Radiological Health Studies
    - Argonne National Laboratory, Late Effects Group, 1964 (Box 43)
    - Colorado State University-U.S. Public Health Service (CSU-PHS) Collaborative Health Laboratory, 1966-1969; 4 folders (Box 43)
    - United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, "Radiation Bio-effects", 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission
    - Advisory Committee
      - Correspondence, 1957-1975; 3 folders (Box 44)
      - Meeting Reports, 1957-1969; 4 folders (Box 44)
    - Publications (Box 44)
    - Trip Report, Japan, 1958 (Box 44)
    - Trip Report, Japan, 1965 (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous, Cold Spring Institute (Putnam County, New York)
    - Autobiographies, 1954-1957; 3 folders (Box 44)
- Photographs
  There are more than 200 photographs in the series Photographs, divided in two subseries, Personal and Professional. Most are labeled and Shock provided an index to these which may be found in the first folder of the series. Each is numbered and the total group covers the period 1901-1983.
  - Index to photographs (Box 44)
  - Personal photographs numbers 1-19, 1901-1981 (Box 44)
  - Professional photographs, 1937-1983
    - Numbers 1-23, 1937-1958 (Box 44)
    - Numbers 25-85, 1961-1968 (Box 44)
    - Numbers 86-131, 1969-1972 (Box 44)
    - Numbers 133-195, 1972-1976 (Box 44)
    - Numbers 197-238, 1977-1983 (Box 44)
    - Past Presidents, International Association of Gerontology numbers 239-249, 1950-1979 (Box 44)
    - Past Presidents, Gerontological Society of America numbers 250-255, 1963-1970 (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous, no numbers (Box 44)
    - "A Brief Photographic History of the Gerontology Research Center", n.d. (Box 44)
    - 25th Anniversary, Baltimore Longitudinal Study on Aging no numbers, September 9-11, 1983 (Box 44)
- Audio-tapes
  The last series, Audio Tapes, numbers approximately 200 tapes in 6 linear feet. Some are labeled. They appear to be tapes of meetings and conferences, but may have little substantive value.
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 45)
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 46)
    (continued)
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 47)
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 48)
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 49)
  - Audio tapes of meetings, conferences, etc.; approximately 200 tapes, some labeled (Box 50)